dokeos.com 2019-10-20

# Privacy Charter and Cookie Management - Dokeos

The present Charter is established by the SPRL Dokeos whose headquarter is located on rue Provinciale, 264 to 1301, Bierges, email address: info@dokeos.com, registration number: BE 0862 938 031 (hereinafter referred to as “Dokeos” or “we”).

 This Charter applies to the website referring to the url : http://www.dokeos.com (hereinafter referred to as the “website”) as well as to all the instances of Dokeos software that are hosted for the account of our customers. Its goal is to inform you of how we collect and process your personal data.

 Dokeos attaches great importance to respect for your privacy and the security of your personal data. We act in full transparency, in accordance with the law of 8 December 1992 on the protection of privacy with regard to the processing of personal data and Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (hereinafter referred to as the “General Data Protection Regulation”or “GDPR”).

 If you wish to respond to any of the practices described below, you may contact us at privacy@dokeos.com

 **Consent**

By accessing the website and using it, you declare to have read the information described below, accept this Charter and expressly consent to our collection and processing, in accordance with the terms and principles described below, your personal data personal that you communicate to us through the website or software, for the purposes indicated below.

You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawal of consent does not compromise the lawfulness of consent-based treatment.

 **What data do we collect?**

By visiting and using the website or browsing Dokeos software, you expressly consent to our collection and processing, according to the terms and principles described below, of your personal data as follows:

  * your home domain (dynamic IP address), which is automatically detected by the server during each visit to the website;

  * if necessary, your e-mail address if you have voluntarily communicated to us, for example via the contact form or request for access to a free portal;

  * information about the pages you viewed on the website;

  * any other information that you have voluntarily communicated to us;

  * the information collected on your Dokeos LMS portal by the manager of this portal within your organization. For example: your performance in the quizzes, your progression in the training courses as well as the training you have followed. This information is entrusted to us by your manager, managed by us and our subcontractors for simple purpose of hosting and we do not exploit them. Our subcontractors are subject to us with the same obligations to respect the confidentiality of your data;

  * We may also have to collect non-personal data. These data are qualified as non-personal data because they do not identify directly or indirectly a particular person. They can therefore be used for any purpose, for example to improve the website or software and the information they contain.

In the event that non-personal data are combined with personal data, so that an identification of data subjects is possible, these data will be treated as personal data until their reconciliation with a particular person is made impossible.

 **How do we collect your data?**

We collect your personal data as follows:

  * when you contact us via the contact form available on the website;

  * when you complete the application form for access to a test portal;

  * when using Dokeos software;

  * by one or more cookie (s).

 **What  purposes do we persue?**

Your personal data are only collected and processed for the purposes mentioned below:

  * answer your questions or comments (for example questions about our software);

  * provide you with a test portal that meets your needs;

  * inform you about our products and services;

  * improve the quality of the website and the information it contains.

 **What is the shelf life of your data?**

We only store your personal data for the time reasonably necessary for the purposes pursued and in accordance with legal and regulatory requirements, for a maximum of two years.

 **What are your rights and how can you exercise them?**

By written, dated and signed request sent to the address referred to privacy@dokeos.com and by justifying your identity (enclosing a copy of your identity card / passport) you can ask us to :

  * obtain free written communication or a copy of your personal data that has been collected. The copy of your data will be communicated to you at the latest within one month after receiving your written request;

  * obtain, as soon as possible and at the latest within one month, free correction of your personal data which would be inaccurate, incomplete or irrelevant, as well as supplementing them if they prove to be incomplete;

  * limit the processing of your personal data, in particular in the following cases:

1) when you dispute the accuracy of a data and only for the time that we can control it;

2) when, although no longer necessary for the pursuit of the purposes of the treatment, you need it for the purpose of exercising or defending your rights in court;

  * obtain the deletion of your personal data, in particular when one of the following reasons applies:

1) your data are no longer necessary for the purposes of the treatment;

2) you have withdrawn your consent to have your data processed and there is no other legal basis for the processing.

 **Who has access to your data?**

Your data is only accessible to Dokeos employees and its subcontractors in the strict framework of the working relationship that binds them to Dokeos and for which they have committed themselves to respect this charter.

We do not disclose your personal information to a third party without your prior consent, unless it is necessary to fulfill your requests, or if we are legally required to do so.

 **Do we use cookies?**

The website uses cookies to make browsing more useful and reliable. Some of these cookies are essential to the functioning of the website, others allow to improve your experience.

Most web browsers are configured to automatically accept cookies. If you want to customize their management, you must change your browser settings. You will find more information about this below.

By visiting and using the website, you expressly agree with the cookie management described below.

Definition: A “cookie” is a file of data or texts that the server of a website temporarily or permanently records on the user’s equipment (hard disk of the computer, tablet, smartphone, or any other similar device) through its browser.

Cookies retain a certain amount of information, such as the language preferences of visitors. Other cookies collect statistics about the users of a website or ensure that the graphics appear correctly and that the applications work well on the website.

 **What types of cookies do we use?**

On the website, we use the following cookies:

Essential or technical cookies: these cookies are essential for the operation of the website, allowing good communication and intended to facilitate navigation;

Statistical or analytic cookies: These cookies are used to recognize and count the number of visitors and to see their browsing behavior when they visit the website. This improves the user’s navigation and makes it easier for him to find what he is looking for;

Functional cookies: these cookies allow the activation of specific functionalities on the website in order to improve the usability and experience of the user, in particular by remembering his choice of preferences (for example the language);

Performance cookies: These cookies collect information about how visitors use the website. They can evaluate and improve the content and performance of the website (for example by counting the number of visitors, by identifying the most popular pages or clicks), and better match the content of the site to preferences the user.

Tracking cookies: The website uses tracking cookies via Google Analytics, in order to help us measure the ways in which users interact with the content of the website, and which generates visit statistics in a strictly anonymous way. These statistics continually improve the website and provide the user with relevant content. We use Google Analytics to get an overview of the traffic to the website, the origin of this traffic and the pages visited. This means that Google acts as a subcontractor. The information collected by Google Analytics is generated as anonymously as possible. For example, it is not possible to identify the people who visit the website. For more information, users should review Google’s data protection policy at http://www.google.nl/intl/en_uk/policies/privacy/

The retention period for cookies varies according to their type: essential cookies are generally kept until the browser closes, while functional cookies remain valid for 1 year and performance cookies are 4 years.

We allow public search engines to visit the website via the ‘spiders’ with the sole purpose of making the access and the content of the website accessible through their search engines, without our giving the right to proceed to archiving the website. We reserve the right to withdraw the authorization at any time as set forth in this article.

 **How can you manage / disable cookies?**

Most browsers are set to accept cookies automatically, but all allow you to customize settings based on user preferences.

If you do not want the website to place cookies on your computer / mobile device, you can easily manage or delete them by changing your browser settings. You can also schedule your browser to send you a notification when you receive a cookie and decide whether to accept it.

If you want to block and / or manage certain cookies, you can do so by following the link linked to your browser:

Internet Explorer: http://windows.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-vista/block-or-allow-cookies

Chrome: https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en

Firefox: https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences

Safari: http://support.apple.com/kb/PH5042

If you do not want to accept cookies from Google Analytics, you can indicate it via the message about cookies that appears on your first visit to the website or by customizing the settings of your browser so that you refuse them. Cookies.

To no longer be traced by Google Analytics on any website, you are invited to visit the following website: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout

In the event that you disable certain cookies, it is possible that parts of the website are not searchable and / or usable or only partially.

 **How do we secure your personal data?**

We implement the appropriate technical and organizational measures to guarantee a level of security of data collecting and processing in relation to the risks presented by the treatment and the nature of the data to be protected. We take into account the state of knowledge, the costs of implementation and the nature, scope, context and purpose of the treatment and the risks to your rights and freedoms.

We always use encryption technologies that are recognized as industry standards within the IT sector when we transfer or receive data on the website.

We have implemented appropriate security measures to protect and prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of information received on the website.

 **File a complaint ?**

If you wish to react to one of the practices described in this Charter, you can contact us at the addresses specified in “privacy@dokeos.com”.

You can lodge a complaint with the Belgian Commission for the Protection of Privacy at the following address:

Commission for the Protection of Privacy

Rue de la Presse, 35

1000 Brussels

Phone : \+ 32 2 274 48 00

Fax : \+ 32 2 274 48 35

commission@privacycommission.be

You can also file a complaint with the court close to your home.

For further information on complaints and possible remedies, you are invited to consult the following address of the Belgian Commission for the Protection of Privacy: https://www.privacycommission.be/de/node/19254

 **How to contact us ?**

For any question and / or complaint, particularly as to the clear and accessible nature of this Charter, you can contact us at the following addresses:

By email: privacy@dokeos.com

By mail: Dokeos SPRL, Provincial Street, 264, 1301 BIERGES

Modification of this Charter

We reserve the right to modify the provisions of this Charter at any time. The changes will be published with a warning as to their coming to effect.

Applicable law and competent jurisdiction

This Charter is governed by Belgian law.

Any dispute relating to the interpretation or the execution of the present Charter will be subject to the Belgian Law and will fall under the exclusive competence of the courts of the judicial district of Nivelles, Belgium.

Last update: May 7, 2018

Pour continuer à naviguer sur ce site, consentez-vous expressément à ce que nous traitions les données relatives à votre personne physique, conformément à la GDPR ? Accepter [En savoir plus](https://www.dokeos.com/fr/charte-vie-privee/)
